Michael was a huge humanitarian.
Yes, he gave away tens of millions of dollars to charity.
You know, Michael Jackson was the biggest pop star of all time.
And when I hear people try to compare pop stars of this era to him, it's like, stop.
When we're talking about Michael Jackson, we're not simply just talking about his music.
We're not talking about his level of fame.
We're not even just talking about where his music charted.
We're talking about how this person lived and how their art informed
how they lived and how they use their art to live in such a valuable way.
And he paid his success forward without social media and 4K.
The little known fact about Michael is the time, the personal time he gave,
quietly, privately visiting hospitals to visit children who were ill or sick.
And he specifically had a prohibition about media.
It wasn't like today, celebrity does something.
I want everybody to know about it.
It's got to be all over Instagram.
No, Michael did it privately.
There weren't cameras following him at the hospitals and at the toy stores,
getting gifts to extend to folks.
Because it came from the heart.
It wasn't for promotion.
It wasn't for marketing.
It's because he cared.
These days, artists at the level of Michael Jackson exist in optics.
Anything that they do has to be a headline.
The biggest pop star that we have known would make statements without any cameras watching because it was the way he lived, not just the way he looked.
That's so inspiring to me as an artist.
A lot of people don't know how much I give of my time, of my effort, of my earnings, etc.
It's a part of the music I make that I live this way.
It's not just an image or some type of branding.
That's why the music that I make is a reflection of that.
The two are in tandem because movement music and revolution music and resistance music doesn't have to just be a certain style like reggae or, you know, Rage Against the Machine, etc.
It literally just has to be music that is grounded in elevating humanity.
And the only way to do that for real is to be about living a life that is grounded in elevating humanity.